bjs.com 2016-06-14

# Privacy Policy - BJs Wholesale Club

BJ’s respects your right to privacy. We appreciate that you care about how your information is collected, used and shared. These highlights briefly summarize: (1) how we collect information from or about you offline, on BJs.com and other web site(s) operated by or for BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc. (“BJ’s Sites”) and in connection with your use of BJ’s Club wireless network service (“BJ’s Wifi”), (2) how we use and share that information, and (3) the choices you have with regard to the collection, use and sharing of that information.

Our privacy practices are governed by the full Privacy Policy which follows these highlights, and we encourage you to take the time to read the full policy.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

We may collect personally identifiable information about you — such as your name, Membership number, postal address, email address, telephone number, driver’s license number and credit card account information — that you provide to us or that we receive from third–party sources. 

We may collect your email address and various types of non–personally identifiable information through BJ’s Sites and BJ’s Wifi, including via the use of cookies, web beacons and similar technology. For BJ’s Wifi, we can also identify the wireless access point to which you are connected, which is associated with your approximate location within a BJ’s Club. We also may collect transactional information about purchases you make in our Clubs or on BJ’s Sites.

We may authorize third parties to collect non–personally identifiable information from you via third–party cookies, on our behalf, in order to deliver advertisements about our products and services that are customized to your preferences when you visit other, non–BJ’s affiliated web sites. These third parties may be online advertising networks that collect information through cookies and similar tools over time and across different websites. 

Read more about the information we collect

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

Like many retailers, we may use the information we collect to process your requests and transactions; improve the operation of our web sites and Clubs; provide you with marketing and promotional information; facilitate, improve and customize the services that we provide to you; and communicate with you about our products and services.

We may combine any of the information, both personally identifiable and non–personally identifiable, that we collect offline, on BJ’s Sites, through your use of BJ’s Wifi and from third–party sources.

Read more about how we use the information we collect

**  
DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES?**

We only share your personally identifiable information with third parties in the following limited situations:

  * with third–party Member Service Partners in conjunction with making special offers available to Members;
  * with product suppliers and other third–party business partners in conjunction with certain marketing activities;
  * with our service providers;
  * as required by law;
  * in response to legal claims;
  * to protect the safety, property or other rights of BJ’s and its Members and employees; or
  * as an integral part of a sale of all or part of our business.

Read more about how we share your information

**WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?**

Most web browsers can be set to block cookies, and you may be able to opt out of the use of certain third–party cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Web site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

To opt out of receiving promotional or marketing emails from BJ’s you may:

  * Click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any promotional or marketing email you receive from BJ’s.
  * Access your Online Profile via the “Login” link on the BJs.com Home Page and update your email marketing preferences. 

To opt out of receiving promotional or marketing material from BJ’s via postal mail, promotional telephone calls from BJ’s or to opt out of the sharing of your information with third parties for marketing purposes, you may:

  * Click on the customer care link on the BJs.com Home Page to email us.
  * Write us at the following address: BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc., Attn: BJ’s Member Care, 25 Research Drive, Westborough, MA 01581.
  * Call BJ’s Member Care at 800–BJS–CLUB (257–2582), Monday – Friday, 9AM – 7PM, Saturday, 9AM – 6PM and Sunday, NOON – 6PM E.T.

Read more about the choices you have

**HOW DO I CONTACT BJ’s?**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us in writing at:

> **BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc.  
>  ****Attn: Member Care  
>  ****25 Research Drive  
>  ****Westborough** **, MA 01581**   
> 

* * *

This Privacy Policy describes BJ’s (“us”, “we”, “our”) privacy practices with respect to information we collect both online (through BJs.com and other web site(s) operated by or for BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc., (“BJ’s Sites”), and in connection with your use of BJ’s Club wireless network service (“BJ’s Wifi”)) and offline about our Members and other customers and visitors.

**COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY**

BJ’s knows that you care about how your information is used and shared. We respect your right to privacy. Your ability to make informed choices about the use of your information is important to us. We want to make sure that you understand the information we collect about you, how it is used, how it is shared and the safeguards that we have in place in order to protect it. This Privacy Policy explains our policy regarding the collection, use, disclosure and protection of information.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We may collect the personally identifiable information (“PII”) that you provide to us, such as when you purchase, renew or modify your BJ’s Membership; make a purchase in our Clubs or on BJ’s Sites; access BJ’s Wifi; participate in surveys or contests; or communicate with us for any reason. The types of PII that we may collect from you include your name, Membership number, postal address, email address, telephone number, driver’s license number and credit card account information. We may also collect transactional information about the purchases you make in our Clubs or on BJ’s Sites. Finally, we may collect certain information, such as your email address, through web beacons as described in more detail in the section titled “Information Collected Through Cookies and Web Beacons” below.

We may receive PII about you from third–party sources, such as service providers, product suppliers and Member Service Partners (i.e., third–party business partners that offer products and services to our Members, including, for example, optical products and travel services). We may combine the PII we collect from you with information we collect from these other sources, both offline and online. The initial collection and sharing of the PII we receive from third parties, including Member Service Partners, is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties, and you should refer to those third parties’ policies to understand how they handle your PII and the choices you have.

We may also, in certain circumstances, combine the PII we collect with the non–PII we collect. For example, when you use BJ’s Sites or BJ’s Wifi, we may combine the non–PII we collect with your email address or other BJ’s Membership information.

**Non–Personally Identifiable Information**

When you visit BJ’s Sites, we may collect non–PII from you, such as your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, your browser type, the referring web site, if any, the items you view or place in your shopping cart on BJ’s Sites, and the path you take through BJ’s Sites. We collect non–PII through a variety of technical methods, including cookies and web beacons. 

When you access BJ’s Wifi, we may collect non–PII from your mobile device, such as Media Access Control (“MAC”) address, association to specific wireless access points (which can be associated with an approximate location within a BJ’s Club), date, time and duration of use, device type and operating system, and the amount of bandwidth used. 

**Information Collected Through Cookies and Web Beacons**

Cookies are pieces of information that any web site may transfer to your browser that are then stored in your computer’s system and which allow BJ’s Sites to recognize you if you return to the Sites using the same computer and browser. We use cookies to store users’ preferences and to record information about your visit to BJ’s Sites. We also use cookies to customize advertising and web page content based on browser type and user profile information. The deposit of cookies by BJ’s Sites may enhance your online experience by allowing us to save your preferences for your next visit. Our cookies may also measure the general activity on BJ’s Sites and measure advertising effectiveness, which allows us to determine which areas and features are most popular. This information allows us to make improvements to BJ’s Sites.

Third parties with whom we have partnered may use “third–party” cookies to collect non–PII from you on our behalf. These third parties will use the non–PII collected via third–party cookies to deliver advertisements about our products and services that are customized to your preferences when you visit other non–BJ’s affiliated web sites on the Internet. These third parties may be online advertising networks that collect information through cookies and similar tools over time and across different websites.

Web beacons, also known as “clear gifs,” “one–pixel gifs,” “web bugs,” “Internet tags” or “pixel tags,” are small graphic images (usually invisible) that can be embedded in content and advertising on a web site or in an email. These may be embedded on BJ’s Sites or on advertisements for BJ’s appearing on third–party web sites or in email. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on your browser, check whether you have viewed a web page or email message, and determine, among other things, the time and date that you viewed the web beacon, the IP address of your computer, and the URL of the web page from which the web beacon was viewed. We, and third parties acting on our behalf, may collect your email address through the use of web beacons when you interact with BJ’s Sites or our email advertising. However, your name, postal address, credit card account information or other PII is not collected by web beacons. 

See the section titled “What Choices Do I Have?” for information on choices available relating to our cookie usage and marketing activities.

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

Like many retailers, the information we collect is generally used to process your requests and transactions, to improve the operation of our web sites and Clubs, to provide you with marketing and promotional information that we believe adds value to your Membership (“Promotional Material”), to customize your experience on BJ’s Sites, to keep track of eligible purchases for BJ’s Rewards® and any other incentive programs, to understand your needs so that we may provide you with the most suitable products and services, and to otherwise communicate with you about our products and services. We may combine any of the information, both personally identifiable and non–personally identifiable, that we collect offline, on BJ’s Sites, through BJ’s Wifi and from third–party sources.

As indicated above, our third–party partners may use, on our behalf, the non–PII that they collect through third–party cookies to deliver advertisements about our products and services that are customized to your preferences when you visit other, non–BJ’s affiliated web sites on the Internet.

**Send–to–a–Friend** : If Members elect to use our referral service for sending information to a friend on BJ’s Sites, we may ask them for the friend’s name and email address. Some email Promotional Material may also contain links to “Send–to–a–Friend.” Any email addresses submitted to BJ’s for the purpose of forwarding Promotional Material to others will not be used for BJ’s mailing lists and will not be collected for re–distribution.

**DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES?**

BJ’s only shares your PII with third parties in the limited situations set forth below. In such situations, we provide only the information necessary to perform the function or to provide the service for which it has been shared. These third parties are not permitted to use the PII provided by us for any purposes other than those authorized by BJ’s, and these third parties are required to otherwise keep the PII confidential.

In addition, BJ’s may share aggregated demographic information and/or customer–profile data with our business partners, advertisers and others. When shared in this form, this is not linked to any PII that can identify any individual person.

**Member Services**

BJ’s may share your PII with our third–party Member Service Partners who are carefully selected partners, that, for the benefit of our Members, we allow to make special offers. Member Service Partners’ web sites and offers may or may not be co–branded. To facilitate Members’ orders with Member Service Partners’ web sites that link to BJ’s Sites, BJ’s may “pre–populate” or permit these sites to recognize and input certain Member PII to avoid repeated re–entry of required information associated with these orders. If you apply for or request certain products or services directly from our Member Service Partners, you may receive information directly from them regarding their products or services.

In addition, we may share your PII with product suppliers and other third–party business partners so they can: (1) offer you benefits, discounts or promotions (for example, special offers from our product suppliers); (2) offer or assist us in offering sweepstakes, contests and other marketing promotions; (3) advise you of upcoming offerings and promotions available through joint, co–branded promotional activities with BJ’s; and (4) conduct research or provide marketing assistance.

In some cases, instead of sharing your PII, we may send you offers on behalf of our third–party business partners, including Member Service Partners. In such cases, those third–party business partners will only have access to your PII if you respond to them directly. Any PII you provide directly to third–party business partners, including Member Service Partners, is subject to those third parties’ own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of the Member Service Partner. We encourage our users to read the privacy policies of all Member Service Partners that collect PII. This BJ’s Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by BJ’s. Should you wish to change your marketing preferences with respect to any Member Service Partner, please be sure to do so by following the instructions contained in their individual privacy policies.

In some cases, third–party business partners may require, as a condition of providing services to you, that you authorize them to share your PII with us. If we terminate our relationship with a third–party business partner, the PII you provided to them may be returned to us, and we may provide that PII to a new third party offering the same or similar services.

**Service Providers**

BJ’s may share your PII with trusted service providers who may provide operational or other support services to our Members, or who perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include providers who fulfill orders, process payments, process rebates, distribute emails, conduct research or provide other marketing assistance.

**Other Disclosures**

BJ’s may share your PII if BJ’s believes, in good faith, that such disclosure is: (a) authorized by law or necessary to comply with a legal process; (b) in response to legal claims; (c) necessary to protect personal safety, property or other rights of BJ’s and its Members or employees; or (d) an integral part of a sale of all or part of our business, including assets, merger or reorganization.

**WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?**

**Choices Regarding the Collection of My Information**

**Cookies:** Most web browsers will allow you to erase cookies, notify you when you receive a new cookie or block them altogether. If you would like to exercise control over BJ’s collection of non–PII via cookies, please use the Help function in your browser to find instructions on how to set your browser’s cookie preferences. If you elect to block cookies from BJ’s Sites, you may be unable to take advantage of many of the opportunities and online features offered by BJ’s Sites.

**Third–Party Cookies:** To opt–out of the collection of your non–PII via third–party cookies and other types of online behavioral advertising, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) to visit the Network Advertising Initiative web site which enables opt–out of participating third–party online advertising networks.

Note: As discussed above, while you may have the opportunity to control the use of cookies through your web browser and via the Network Advertising Initiative web site, we do not otherwise currently respond to web browser “do not track” signals. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this privacy policy. For more information about do not track, visit [www.allaboutdnt.org](http://allaboutdnt.com/). 

**BJ’s Wifi:** If you do not want non–PII collected from your mobile device through BJ’s Wifi, you should not agree to use BJ’s Wifi. Once you have agreed to use BJ’s Wifi, you can stop the collection of non–PII through BJ’s Wifi by changing your mobile device settings to not connect to BJ’s Wifi upon return to a BJ’s Club. If you elect not to use BJ’s Wifi, you may be unable to take advantage of mobile coupons or other offers provided through BJ’s Wifi.

**Choices Regarding the Use of My Information**

We give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving Promotional Material from BJ’s or the sharing of your information with Member Service Partners and other third–party business partners for marketing purposes. Your choice to opt out will apply only to the Memberships sharing the same Membership Number (Primary Members and Household Members share the same Membership Number).

**Email:** To indicate that you do not want to receive Promotional Material via email or to change the frequency with which Promotional Material is sent via email, you may:

  * Click on the unsubscribe link on the bottom of any promotional email that you receive from BJ’s as the sender to access the Email Preference Center.
  * Access your Online Account via the “Sign in” link on the BJs.com Home Page and update your email marketing preferences by clicking on the subscribe/unsubscribe link.

**Direct Mail or Telemarketing** : To indicate that you do not want to receive Promotional Material via postal mail or to receive promotional telephone calls, you may:

  * Click on the Customer care link on the BJs.com Home Page to email us.
  * Write us at the following address: BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc., Attn: BJ’s Member Care, 25 Research Drive, Westborough, MA 01581.
  * Call BJ’s Member Care at 800–BJS–CLUB (257–2582), Monday – Friday, 9AM – 7PM, Saturday, 9AM – 6PM and Sunday, NOON – 6PM E.T.

**Third–Party Sharing:** If you prefer that we do not share your information with Member Service Partners and other third–party business partners for marketing purposes, you may:

  * Click on the Customer care link on the BJs.com Home Page to email us.
  * Write us at the following address: BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc., Attn: BJ’s Member Care, 25 Research Drive, Westborough, MA 01581.
  * Call BJ’s Member Care at 800–BJS–CLUB (257–2582), Monday – Friday, 9AM – 7PM, Saturday, 9AM – 6PM and Sunday, NOON – 6PM E.T.

Please be advised that even if you choose to opt out of all forms of communication from BJ’s, you will continue to receive communications regarding product safety alerts, as well as Membership renewal information.

**HOW DO I ACCESS MY INFORMATION?**

You may update, review or correct your account information by:

  * Accessing your Online Account via the “Sign in” link on the BJs.com Home Page by clicking on the subscribe/unsubscribe link.
  * Calling BJ’s Member Care at 800–BJS–CLUB (257–2582), Monday – Friday, 9AM – 7PM, Saturday, 9AM – 6PM and Sunday, NOON – 6PM E.T.
  * Writing us at the following address: BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc., Attn: BJ’s Member Care, 25 Research Drive, Westborough, MA 01581.

**IS MY INFORMATION SECURE?**

BJ’s is committed to maintaining the security of information under our control. To try to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect the information we collect. Any information collected on BJ’s Sites is located on a secure server located behind a firewall and is not directly connected to the Internet. BJ’s employs Secure Socket Layer software and password protection procedures to safeguard PII collected.

**INFORMATION ABOUT CHILDREN UNDER 13**

BJ’s Sites are general audience web sites and are not targeted to children under 13 years of age. BJ’s does not knowingly collect or store the PII of children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have PII about a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. To make you aware of material changes to this policy, we will post the date the policy was last revised at the top of the policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of BJ’s Sites, patronage of our Clubs or interaction with BJ’s, constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Members and other customers and visitors who reside in California, and who have provided their PII to BJ’s, may request information about our sharing of certain categories of PII with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in writing at the contact address at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve the right to not respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified below.

**HOW DO I CONTACT BJ’s?**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us in writing at:

> **BJ’s Wholesale Club, Inc.  
>  ****Attn: Member Care  
>  ****25 Research Drive  
>  ****Westborough, MA 01581**

Effective: January 15, 2013 (Updated January 7, 2014)
